<course>
<title>POJOs: Plain Old Java Objects</title>
<specs>
	<coursenumber>8001</coursenumber>
	<programs><program>Graduate in Complementary Studies in Applied Informatics: Java Development for the Enterprise</program></programs>
	<a>37.5</a>
	<b>22.5</b>
	<c />
	<d>180</d>
	<e>6</e>
	<department>CSE02</department>
	<language>English</language>
	<lecturers>
		<lecturer inCharge="true">Chris Richardson</lecturer>
	</lecturers>
</specs>
<tagline>Developing Enterprise Applications with Lightweight Frameworks.</tagline>
<description>
In the past, developers built enterprise Java applications using EJB
technologies that are excessively complex and difficult to use. Often EJB
introduced more problems than it solved. There is a major trend in the
industry towards using simpler and easier technologies such as Hibernate,
Spring, JDO, iBATIS and others, all of which allow the developer to work
directly with the simpler Plain Old Java Objects or POJOs. Now EJB version 3
solves the problems that gave EJB 2 a black eye--it too works with POJOs.<newline />
In this course, we'll discover new, easier ways to develop enterprise Java
applications and how to make key design decisions when developing
business logic using POJOs, including how to organize and encapsulate the
business logic, access the database, manage transactions, and handle
database concurrency. The student will be able to successfully build
lightweight applications that are easier to develop, test, and maintain.</description>
<contents>
	<topic>How to develop apps in the post EJB 2 world</topic>
	<topic>How to leverage the strengths and work around the weaknesses of: JDO, Hibernate, and EJB 3</topic>
	<topic>How to benefit by using aspects</topic>
	<topic>How to do test-driven development with lightweight frameworks</topic>
	<topic>How to accelerate the edit-compile-debug cycle</topic>
</contents>
<book>
<img src="8001.jpg" border="0" alt="POJOs in Action" align="Left" />
POJOs in Action<newline />by Chris Richardson<newline />(October 2005, 450 pages)<newline />
ISBN: 1932394583</book>
</course>