<course>
<title>Eclipse</title>
<specs>
	<coursenumber>8010</coursenumber>
	<programs><program>Graduate in Complementary Studies in Applied Informatics: Java Development for the Enterprise</program></programs>
	<a>15</a>
	<b>15</b>
	<c />
	<d>90</d>
	<e>3</e>
	<department>CSE02</department>
	<language>English</language>
	<lecturers>
		<lecturer inCharge="true">David Gallardo</lecturer>
		<lecturer>Ed Burnette</lecturer>
		<lecturer>Robert McGovern</lecturer>
	</lecturers>
</specs>
<tagline>Eclipse is a new open-source, Java-based, extensible development platform
designed for nothing in particular but everything in general.</tagline>
<description>
Because of its roots, Eclipse is currently most popular
as a Java integrated development environment (IDE).
Eclipse ships with plugins for writing and debugging Java code.
Additional plugins for more advanced Java development,
such as JSP/servlets, are available from third parties.<newline />
This course offers realistic examples that demonstrate
how to use Eclipse effectively to build, test and debug
applications using the tools provided by Eclipse and
other third-party open source plugins.
The student will learn how to use plugin tools for
using Eclipse in a team environment, including using Ant
for more sophisticated build processes and CVS for source control.
Plugin-ins for building web applications, using J2EE technologies,
such as JSP/Servlets and EJB, are also discussed.
</description>
<contents>
<topic>Getting started with the Eclipse Workbench: Perspectives, views and editors</topic>
<topic>Working effectively with the Eclipse JDT</topic>
<topic>Adding unit tests with JUnit, logging with log4j</topic>
<topic>Team development with Ant and CVS</topic>
<topic>Plugins for J2EE including the Sysdeo Tomcat plugin</topic>
<topic>Developing Eclipse plugins</topic>
<topic>Comprehensive Eclipse reference</topic>
</contents>
<book>
<img src="8010.jpg" border="0" alt="Eclipse in Action" align="Left" />
Eclipse in Action<newline/>
by David Gallardo, Ed Burnette and Robert McGovern<newline/>
(May 2003, 416 pages)<newline/>
ISBN: 1930110960</book>
</course>