<course>
<title>Implementing the database layer with Hibernate</title>
<specs>
	<coursenumber>8020</coursenumber>
	<programs><program>Graduate in Complementary Studies in Applied Informatics: Java Development for the Enterprise</program></programs>
	<a>37.5</a>
	<b>22.5</b>
	<c />
	<d>120</d>
	<e>4</e>
	<department>CSE02</department>
	<language>English</language>
	<lecturers>
		<lecturer inCharge="true">Christian Bauer</lecturer>
		<lecturer>Gavin King</lecturer>
	</lecturers>
</specs>
<tagline>Persisting your Java objects to a relational database.</tagline>
<description>Hibernate practically exploded on the Java scene. Why is this 
open-source tool so popular? Because it automates a tedious task: 
persisting your Java objects to a relational database. The inevitable 
mismatch between your object-oriented code and the relational database 
requires you to write code that maps one to the other. This code is 
often complex, tedious and costly to develop. Hibernate does the mapping 
for you.<newline />
Not only that, Hibernate makes it easy. Positioned as a layer between 
your application and your database, Hibernate takes care of loading and 
saving of objects. Hibernate applications are cheaper, more portable, 
and more resilient to change. And they perform better than anything you 
are likely to develop yourself.<newline />
This course carefully explains the concepts you need, then gets 
you going. It builds on a single example to show you how to use 
Hibernate in practice, how to deal with concurrency and transactions, how 
to efficiently retrieve objects and use caching.
</description>
<contents>
<topic>ORM concepts</topic>
<topic>Getting started</topic>
<topic>Many real-world tasks</topic>
<topic>The Hibernate application development processes</topic>
</contents>
<book>
<img src="8020.jpg" border="0" alt="Hibernate in Action" align="Left" />
Hibernate in Action<newline/>
Christian Bauer and Gavin King<newline/>
(August 2004, 400 pages)<newline/>
ISBN: 193239415X</book>
</course>