<course>
<title>The Spring Framework</title>
<specs>
<coursenumber>8031</coursenumber>
<programs><program>Graduate in Complementary Studies in Applied Informatics: Java Development for the Enterprise</program></programs>
<a>37.5</a>
<b>22.5</b>
<c />
<d>120</d>
<e>4</e>
<department>CSE02</department>
<language>English</language>
<lecturers>
<lecturer inCharge="true">Craig Walls</lecturer>
<lecturer>Ryan Breidenbach</lecturer>
</lecturers>
</specs>
<tagline>Inversion of Control and Aspect Oriented Programming.</tagline>
<description>
Spring is a fresh breeze blowing over the Java landscape. Based on a 
design principle called Inversion of Control, Spring is a powerful but 
lightweight J2EE framework that does not require the use of EJBs. Spring 
greatly reduces the complexity of using interfaces, and speeds and 
simplifies your application development. You get the power and robust 
features of EJB and get to keep the simplicity of the non-enterprise 
JavaBean.<newline />
This course introduces you to the ideas behind Spring and then 
quickly launches into a hands-on exploration of the framework. Combining 
short code snippets and an ongoing example developed throughout the 
book, it shows you how to build simple and efficient J2EE applications. 
You will see how to solve persistence problems using the leading 
open-source tools, and also how to integrate your application with the 
most popular web frameworks. You will learn how to use Spring to manage 
the bulk of your infrastructure code so you can focus on what really 
matters: your critical business needs.
</description>

<contents>
<topic>Persistence using Hibernate, JDO, iBatis, OJB, and JDBC</topic>
<topic>Declarative transactions and transaction management</topic>
<topic>Integration with web frameworks: Struts, WebWork, Tapestry, Velocity</topic>
<topic>Accessing J2EE services such as JMS and EJB</topic>
<topic>Addressing cross-cutting concerns with AOP</topic>
<topic>Enterprise applications best practices</topic>
</contents>

<book>
<img src="8031.jpg" border="0" alt="Spring in Action" align="Left" />
Spring in Action<newline/>
Craig Walls and Ryan Breidenbach<newline/>
(February 2005, 472 pages)<newline/>
ISBN: 1932394354</book>
</course>